hello welcome to the Mineiro data channel
today for another miner answers
today's question came from Kellen from the
Federal University of Amazonas
bringing Tatiana she had the
following problem she had a
GDF dot file and she wanted to open it in the
voice viewer it turns out that if you go here
in voz Vivo and try to open this type
of file you will see that the options
that exist the voice format itself
Viva o Jason that is created by voz
viller the gml format and the
payek format, right, which has a grandson orfael and also
has the partister as optional well the gml
sometimes works as an option Sometimes
we manage to transform it into a gml but
in general depending on the origin that
this GDF came from it turns out that it is better for
us to try to make this transfer
from the Pajé's format, right, and that's
exactly what we're going to do,
first of all, we're
going to get the gaffe, which is another tool.
which would be its GDF file I'm going to
take here an example of a GDF that I
have which is this Rede Ponto GDF and I'm going to
ask it to be opened it's already
being imported here it has 112 nodes 499 are
edges that we are having here
so Let's create this with a new one.
just got the network there is
no type of layout applied you can
previously apply a layout here if
you want from the gaffe itself to later
take it to voz viva or you can apply
the one from vozview i will apply any layout
here in this case i will use the
flow
I ran this layout and now I'm going to export
this material because if I try to save it through the
gaf the gaffe will save in the
gafe format which is not accepted there but it has
export options in
graphic file format which is in this
fly option I have some options one of them
for example is exactly the gml that we have
here that we are going to save once just
in case putting it here as
gml tests you will see that in options
Here there are a series of attributes that
can be seen about it but not this is the
case we are not going to use it and I will
save it
ready and I will also export this
file here again but now in
another format that is the format of Pai
Eco Pajé as if they think it is better to
be called Ok I will put it here
which is dot net in this format it will be
teste.net there are also own options
here that we already leave the for and
I'll just save I'll confirm and
it's saved here well finished this
part inside the ghast we'll take
it now for live voice I give Open you won't
see I'll get the Pajé format here
which is the safest that it will work I'll go
there in my folder to show
you let me get my folder
here
ready
teste.net I'll give ok and I'll give ok here
This one is imported, which happens to be
a graph. I made it for my former
doctoral advisor, Dr.
Eleonora Corten Bar. If the survey
had been done, it's presented here
as with relationships between researchers.
Everything is fine, based on
specific data from a database
I can now apply some other
things for example This is the format that
we know the layout that was brought there
from the gaf which is Fruit but here in
analyzes I can click here and
update the clustering part what it will
mean that he will colonize
this here when I did this he
applied the colorization let's just do it and
come back here because of the video card defense
he applied the colonization which is
the colonization of the GF specific to the voice of the
book specifically but this one layout is
a GF layout with the colonization done
by the voice I can also apply it to
update the layout to have a
Rose viewer layout if I click here on the
update layout it will
ask me if I want to have
112 total items or just the 105 that are
connected to the giant component this is
an analysis with voice
I'll give it here eh Yes I want to stay just
this set specifically 75
and he already did here in the end
went back here to solve the
video card problem he already made it in a type of
graphic with the layout of vozviller option
from you to you is that you know
my name that I was guiding from
Eleonora So it's showing up here it's
good good I hope you like this
video you already know how you like it do it
to take it here Just so it doesn't end
like this without saying that you can also
save this content here and you one of the
ways to save it possible to save either
in gnl or empajec to also go back there
to the gaf if you save it in ml the gef
can do it open it from the other end to
come here, it has to serve for JAC,
okay, there's this little difference there, there's already
a little bit of it here are defects in
my video card that cause this
phenomenon along with live voice, well if you
liked this video, don't let me give the
like promote the channel call your friends
show that you are learning
super cool things about networks ok leave your
thumbs up there a hug kisses and until the
next video